Guide to the Ari Kiev Papers, 1965-2005 K0006
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Ari Kiev papers
1947-2005
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Kiev, Ari
K0006
10.5 Linear Feet 10 document boxes, 3 flat boxes, 3 record cartons, 1 reel
This collection documents the work of psychiatrist Dr. Ari Kiev from 1965 to 2005 through his publications, correspondence, audio and video recordings, legal work, as well as a small quantity of family papers. Kiev's research and private practice covered a wide range of specialties, including depression and suicide prevention, psychopharmacological research, transcultural psychiatry, and the psychology of world-class athletes and Wall Street traders. In addition to his significant record of publication of academic articles and books, Kiev also wrote for a popular audience, particularly with his compact book A Strategy for Daily Living and his guides for Wall Street traders such as Trading to Win, Trading in the Zone, and Hedge Fund Masters.
Scope and Contents
This collection documents the work of psychiatrist Dr. Ari Kiev through his publications, correspondence, audio and video recordings, legal work, as well as a small quantity of family papers. Professional materials date from 1965 to 2005, with some family papers dating to 1921.
Kiev's research and private practice covered a wide range of specialties, including depression and suicide prevention, psychopharmacological research, transcultural psychiatry, and the psychology of world-class athletes and Wall Street traders.
These documents and audiovisual materials were created as part of Kiev's work as a research psychiatrist, author, expert witness, and television personality. In addition to his significant record of publication of academic articles and books, Kiev also wrote for a popular audience, particularly with his compact book A Strategy for Daily Living and his guides for Wall Street traders such as Trading to Win, Trading in the Zone, and Hedge Fund Masters.
Biographical / Historical
Dr. Ari Nissan Kiev was born December 30, 1933 in the Bronx, the son of Rabbi I. Edward Kiev. A psychiatrist, lawyer, and popular author, Kiev specialized in suicide prevention, antidepressant medication investigation, and the psychology of world-class athletes and Wall Street traders.
Kiev received his bachelor's degree from Harvard University in 1954 and his medical degree from Cornell University Medical School in 1958. He completed a residency in psychiatry at Johns Hopkins Hospital, and spent a year as a research fellow at the Institute of Psychiatry at Maudsley Hospital in London. In 1962, he became a U.S. Air Force staff psychiatrist at Lackland Air Force Base in Texas, and in 1967 he returned to Cornell to lead its Program in Social Psychiatry. Kiev published extensively in his field, and many of his draft and published academic articles are available in the collection.
Kiev was the founder and director of the Social Psychiatry Research Institute, which specializes in conducting clinical trials of new prescription drugs. In addition to his work with SPRI, Kiev maintained a private clinical practice, testified as an expert witness in suicide and psychopharmacology cases, and developed the Life Strategy Workshops seminars, tapes of which are available in the collection. In 1975, Kiev taught a class as part of the popular CBS Sunrise Semester program based on his 1964 book Magic, Faith, and Healing: Studies in Primitive Psychiatry, tapes of which are also available in the collection.
Kiev became interested in the psychology of athletic performance in the 1970s, and began working with Olympic athletes on managing stress, eventually as part of the U.S. Olympic Committee's sports medicine committee. His work with top athletes caught the interest of hedge fund manager Steven A. Cohen of SAC Capital Advisors, and Kiev began working with Wall Street traders in 1992, a practice that led to several books on mastering stress in the Wall Street environment.
Kiev was the author or editor of a number of books in psychology and psychiatry, including The Mental Strategies of Top Traders, Hedge Fund Leadership, Hedge Fund Masters, The Psychology of Risk, Trading in the Zone, Trading to Win, A Strategy for Daily Living, Breaking Free of Birth Order, How to Keep Love Alive, The Courage to Live, Recovery from Depression, Magic, Faith, and Healing: Studies in Primitive Psychiatry Today, and Psychiatry in the Communist World.
After years of testifying as an expert witness, Kiev returned to law school at age 50, graduating from New York Law School in 1988. At the time of his death in 2009, he was working toward a masters degree in executive health at George Washington University.
Arrangement
Organized into four series: Writing and documents; Correspondence; Seminars and workshops; and Audiovisual and images.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Ari Kiev, 2008 (2008.010)
Psychiatry; Kiev, Ari
- Writing and documents, 1964-2005; Series 1; 3.5 Linear Feet 7 document boxes
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains draft articles, published articles, and book manuscripts written by Ari Kiev between 1962 and 2007, in addition to other professional materials such as curriculum vitae, diplomas, certificates, and articles written about Kiev by others. It also contains a small number of Kiev family papers including letters and official documents that date as early as 1921.
  Arrangement
  Arranged alphabetically by type of document.
  - Articles in bound periodicals, 1964-1969; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Articles in bound periodicals, 1980-1993; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Articles in bound periodicals, 1994-1997; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Articles in bound periodicals, 1998-2000; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Articles in bound periodicals, 2001-2005; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Articles -- draft, 1968-1985; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Articles -- draft, 1991-2005; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Articles -- draft, Nautilus Magazine, 1982-1983; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Articles -- published, 1968-1989; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Articles -- published, 1992-2006; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Articles -- published, Medical Tribune, 1981-1984; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Articles -- published, Medical Tribune, 1985-1990; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Articles -- published, Nautilus Magazine, 1982; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Article reprints, 1962-1971; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Article reprints, 1972-1976; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Article reprints, 1977-1999; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Articles about Ari Kiev, 1974-1989; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Articles about Ari Kiev, 1990-2005; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Bibliographies, undated; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Cornell University, Weill Medical College, 2003-2004; Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - The Courage to Be -- proposal, 1993; Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Cultural Factors in Leadership Behavior, 1994; Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Curriculum Vitae, 1994-1999; Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Diplomas and certificates, 1958-2007; Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Edited manuscripts [1 of 2], undated; Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Edited manuscripts [2 of 2], undated; Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Family papers, 1921-1965; Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Handwritten manuscript draft, 1988; Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Handwritten manuscript drafts [1 of 3], 1992; Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Handwritten manuscript drafts [2 of 3], 1992; Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Handwritten manuscript drafts [3 of 3], 1992; Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Hedge Fund Masters -- edited manuscript, undated; Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Mastery of Fear -- edited manuscript portions, undated; Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - The Mastery of Fear -- table of contents and introduction, 2003; Series 1 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - The Mind of Man, undated; Series 1 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Notes, undated; Series 1 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Publications on cross-examination, 1996; Series 4 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Reviews of Kiev books, 1964-2002; Series 1 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Russian manuscript, undated; Series 1 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Social Psychiatry Research Institute newsletters and press releases, 1972-1998; Series 1 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Social Psychiatry: Volume 1, Series 1 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Trading to Win, undated; Series 1 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Trading to Win -- edited manuscript [1 of 2], 1998; Series 1 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Trading to Win -- edited manuscript [2 of 2], 1998; Series 1 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Trading to Win -- proposal, Series 1 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Verdicts in Kiev expert witness cases, 1985-1994; Series 4 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Yearbooks, 1957-1958; Series 1 (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Correspondence, 1967-2005; Series 2; 1 Linear Feet 2 document boxes
  Arranged alphabetically by topic of correspondence.
  This series contains correspondence Dr. Kiev received from 1967 to 2005.
  - Appointments and letters of recommendation, 1967-1998; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1976-2004; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence re: publications, 1969-2004; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Invitations, 2001-2005; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - I. Edward Kiev Library Foundation, 1976-2005; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Pharmaceuticals, 1947-1997; Series 2 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Social Psychiatry Research Institute, 1976-2001; Series 2 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Speaking engagements and conferences, 1975-2005; Series 2 (Box 8, Folder 3)
- Seminars, workshops, and certificates, 1970-2003; Series 3; 1 Linear Feet 2 document boxes
  Arranged alphabetically by title.
  This series contains notes, transcripts, and background information on seminars and workshops hosted by Dr. Kiev, including Strategies for Daily Living, Master Your Fears, and Sunrise Semester.
  - [Certificates and acknowledgements of being a Fellow], 1970-1995; Series 3 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Grasping the Competitive Edge seminar, 2003; Series 3 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Life Strategy Workshop -- transcript, undated; Series 3 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Master Your Fears class, undated; Series 3 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Presentation notes, 2000; Series 3 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Strategies for Daily Living seminars, undated; Series 3 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Sunrise Semester, undated; Series 3 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Trading Psychology seminar, 2003; Series 3 (Box 9, Folder 4)
- Audiovisual and photographs, 1975-2003; Series 4; 5 Linear Feet 3 record cartons, 3 flat boxes, 1 reel
  Arranged by material format.
  This series contains audiocassettes, videocassettes, and audio reels of Dr. Ari Kiev's seminars, lectures, and interviews from 1975 through 2003. It also contains a small number of photographs. Audiotapes are available from seminars including Life Strategy Workshops/Strategies for Daily Living and The Mastery of Fear, as well as for Kiev's 1975 CBS Sunrise Semester program based on his 1964 book Magic, Faith, and Healing: Studies in Primitive Psychiatry. Videocassettes are available for Kiev's appearances on CNN, CNBC, MSNBC, the Oprah Winfrey show, the Charlie Rose show, and Fox News.
  - Anxiety, Stress and Panic guidebook and tapes, 1987; Series 4 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Ari Kiev on Charlie Rose [1 of 2], 07/22/1993; Series 4 (Box 12, Videocassette 1)
  - Ari Kiev on Charlie Rose [2 of 2], 07/22/1993; Series 4 (Box 12, Videocassette 2)
  - Ari Kiev M.D. Sales One, 11/1984; Series 4; U-matic videocassette (Box 14, Videocassette data_value_missing_db09f3d1e173470e13ab565f2191677f)
  - Ari Kiev - Pershing Trading Co. Traders Conference, 03/1999; Series 4 (Box 12, Videocassette 3)
  - Ari Kiev - The Psychology of the Market and its Participants, 10/18/2002; Series 4 (Box 13, Videocassette 11)
  - Ari Kiev - The Psychology of the Market and its Participants, 10/18/2002; Series 4 (Box 12, Videocassette 5)
  - Becoming a Disciplined Trader: Techniques for Achieving Peak Trading Performance, undated; Series 4 (Box 12, Dvd 1)
  - Bloomberg Forum - Dr. Ari Kiev, 07/22/2002; Series 4 (Box 13, Videocassette 10)
  - Bloomberg segment - Dr. Ari Kiev, undated; Series 4 (Box 13, Videocassette 19)
  - CLSA Forum - Ari Kiev speech [1 of 2], 09/26/2003; Series 4 (Box 13, Videocassette 16)
  - CLSA Forum - Ari Kiev speech [2 of 2], undated; Series 4 (Box 13, Videocassette 17)
  - CNBC, 09/14/2001; Series 4 (Box 13, Videocassette 7)
  - CNN Before Hours - Dr. Ari Kiev, 08/13/2001; Series 4 (Box 13, Videocassette 6)
  - CNN - Frankel reports, Series 4 (Box 13, Videocassette 23)
  - CNN - Lou Walters, 03/23/2001; Series 4 (Box 13, Videocassette 4)
  - CNN FN Christmas 2001, Series 4 (Box 13, Videocassette 8)
  - CNN Live -- Interview Dr. Ari Kiev, 07/16/2002; Series 4 (Box 13, Videocassette 9)
  - Day Trading, undated; Series 4 (Box 13, Videocassette 24)
  - Dr. Ari Kiev, 08/08/2001; Series 4 (Box 13, Videocassette 5)
  - Dr. Ari Kiev, 03/2001; Series 4 (Box 13, Videocassette 20)
  - Dr. Ari Kiev - CNN, undated; Series 4 (Box 13, Videocassette 21)
  - Dr. Ari Kiev - O'Reilly Factor - Fox News, 01/13/2001; Series 4 (Box 12, Videocassette 4)
  - E.S. Seminar, 11/20/2003; Series 4 (Box 13, Videocassette 18)
  - Eyewitness News, 01/01/1985; Series 4 (Box 13, Videocassette 1)
  - Fear, undated; Series 4 (Box 10, Reel 4)
  - Fox on $, 02/27/1999; Series 4 (Box 13, Videocassette 2)
  - Kiev excerpts, 04/19/1983; Series 4; U-matic videocassette (Box 14, Videocassette 16)
  - Kiev interview - News Biz Today, 11/26/2003; Series 4 (Box 13, Videocassette 15)
  - Kiev - sports psychiatry, undated; Series 4; U-matic videocassette (Box 14, Videocassette 13)
  - Life Strategy Workshops 1 and 2, 11/14/1986; Series 4 (Box 12, Cassette 6)
  - Life Strategy Workshops 7 and 8, 11/14/1986; Series 4 (Box 12, Cassette 7)
  - Life Strategy Workshops 11 and 12, undated; Series 4 (Box 12, Cassette 8)
  - Life Strategy Workshops 15 and 16, 11/14/1986; Series 4 (Box 12, Cassette 9)
  - Life Strategy Workshops 17 and 18, Series 4 (Box 12, Cassette 10)
  - Mastering Your Fears, 04/1992; Series 4 (Box 11, Cassette 32)
  - The Mastery of Fear - Introductory Seminar, undated; Series 4 (Box 11, Cassette 33)
  - The Mastery of Fear - Introductory Seminar, Series 4 (Box 12, Cassette 5)
  - The Mastery of Fear - Parts 1 and 2, undated; Series 4 (Box 11, Cassette 34)
  - The Mastery of Fear - Parts 3 and 4, undated; Series 4 (Box 11, Cassette 35)
  - The Mastery of Fear - Parts 5 and 6, undated; Series 4 (Box 11, Cassette 36)
  - The Mastery of Fear - Parts 7 and 8, undated; Series 4 (Box 11, Cassette 37)
  - The Mastery of Fear - Parts 9 and 10, undated; Series 4 (Box 11, Cassette 38)
  - The Mastery of Fear - Parts 11 and 12, undated; Series 4 (Box 11, Cassette 39)
  - The Mastery of Fear - Parts 13 and 14, undated; Series 4 (Box 12, Cassette 1)
  - The Mastery of Fear for weeks 12 and 13, Series 4 (Box 12, Cassette 2)
  - The Mastery of Fear for weeks 14 and 15, Series 4 (Box 12, Cassette 3)
  - The Mastery of Fear - side A and side B, Series 4 (Box 12, Cassette 4)
  - The Mastery of Fear - Relaxation tape, undated; Series 4 (Box 16, Cassette 17)
  - The Mastery of Fear - 1. Understanding Fear, undated; Series 4 (Box 16, Cassette 18)
  - The Mastery of Fear - 2. Background Factors, undated; Series 4 (Box 16, Cassette 19)
  - The Mastery of Fear - 3. Basic Techniques, undated; Series 4 (Box 16, Cassette 20)
  - The Mastery of Fear - 4. The Vicious Circle, undated; Series 4 (Box 16, Cassette 21)
  - The Mastery of Fear - 5. The Life Principle, undated; Series 4 (Box 16, Cassette 22)
  - The Mastery of Fear - 6. Changing Emotional Responses, undated; Series 4 (Box 16, Cassette 23)
  - The Mastery of Fear - 7. Creating a New Vision, undated; Series 4 (Box 16, Cassette 24)
  - The Mastery of Fear - 8. Letting Go of the Past, undated; Series 4 (Box 16, Cassette 25)
  - The Mastery of Fear - 9. Asserting Yourself, undated; Series 4 (Box 16, Cassette 26)
  - The Mastery of Fear - 10. Inventing New Behavior, undated; Series 4 (Box 16, Cassette 27)
  - The Mastery of Fear - 11. Living in the Here and Now, undated; Series 4 (Box 16, Cassette 28)
  - The Mastery of Fear - 12. Risk Taking, undated; Series 4 (Box 16, Cassette 29)
  - The Mastery of Fear - 13. Living in the Gap, undated; Series 4 (Box 16, Cassette 30)
  - The Mastery of Fear - 14. Living your Commitment, undated; Series 4 (Box 16, Cassette 31)
  - The Mastery of Fear - 15. Radical Transformation, undated; Series 4 (Box 16, Cassette 32)
  - MBF Symposium [tape 2], 05/01/2003; Series 4 (Box 13, Videocassette 12)
  - MBF Symposium [tape 3], 05/01/2003; Series 4 (Box 13, Videocassette 13)
  - MSNBC, 02/26/2000; Series 4 (Box 13, Videocassette 3)
  - Oprah, undated; Series 4 (Box 13, Videocassette 22)
  - People are Talking, 04/19/1983; Series 4; U-matic videocassette (Box 14, Videocassette 15)
  - Photographs mostly of Ari Kiev, undated; Series 4 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    General
    One image (not with Ari Kiev) includes Albert Einstein.
  - The Psychology of Risk - 2003 New York Mercantile Exchange Derivatives Symposium, Series 4 (Box 13, Videocassette 14)
  - Relationships - Active and Passive Love, 12/07/1976; Series 4 (Box 10, Reel 6)
  - Psychodynamic Research Corporation: Alcohol [1 of 2], undated; Series 4 (Box 11, Cassette 14)
  - Psychodynamic Research Corporation: Alcohol [2 of 2], undated; Series 4 (Box 11, Cassette 15)
  - SPRI - Depression New York, Depression New Jersey, undated; Series 4 (Box 13, Videocassette 25)
  - Strains in the Male-Female Relationship, Reel 1, undated; Series 4 (Box 10, Reel 7)
  - Strains in the Male-Female Relationship, Reel 2, undated; Series 4 (Box 10, Reel 8)
  - Strategies for Daily Living (Life Strategy Seminars) - Introduction, undated; Series 4 (Box 11, Cassette 19)
  - Strategies for Daily Living (Life Strategy Seminars) - Introduction, undated; Series 4 (Box 16, Cassette 1)
  - Strategies for Daily Living (Life Strategy Seminars) - Relaxation/Visualization, undated; Series 4 (Box 11, Cassette 20)
  - Strategies for Daily Living (Life Strategy Seminars) - Relaxation/Visualization, undated; Series 4 (Box 16, Cassette 2)
  - Strategies for Daily Living (Life Strategy Seminars) - Relationships, undated; Series 4 (Box 11, Cassette 21)
  - Strategies for Daily Living (Life Strategy Seminars) - Relationships, undated; Series 4 (Box 16, Cassette 3)
  - Strategies for Daily Living (Life Strategy Seminars) - A Worthy Purpose/Your Hidden Potential, undated; Series 4 (Box 11, Cassette 22)
  - Strategies for Daily Living (Life Strategy Seminars) - A Worthy Purpose/Your Hidden Potential, undated; Series 4 (Box 16, Cassette 4)
  - Strategies for Daily Living (Life Strategy Seminars) - Decision Making, undated; Series 4 (Box 11, Cassette 23)
  - Strategies for Daily Living (Life Strategy Seminars) - Decision Making, undated; Series 4 (Box 16, Cassette 5)
  - Strategies for Daily Living (Life Strategy Seminars) - Eliminating Fear, undated; Series 4 (Box 11, Cassette 24)
  - Strategies for Daily Living (Life Strategy Seminars) - Eliminating Fear, undated; Series 4 (Box 16, Cassette 6)
  - Strategies for Daily Living (Life Strategy Seminars) - The Power to Change, undated; Series 4 (Box 11, Cassette 25)
  - Strategies for Daily Living (Life Strategy Seminars) - The Power to Change, undated; Series 4 (Box 16, Cassette 7)
  - Strategies for Daily Living (Life Strategy Seminars) - The Art of Communication, undated; Series 4 (Box 11, Cassette 26)
  - Strategies for Daily Living (Life Strategy Seminars) - The Art of Communication, undated; Series 4 (Box 16, Cassette 8)
  - Strategies for Daily Living (Life Strategy Seminars) - Growth through Relationships, undated; Series 4 (Box 11, Cassette 31)
  - Strategies for Daily Living (Life Strategy Seminars) - Growth through Relationships, undated; Series 4 (Box 16, Cassette 16)
  - Strategies for Daily Living (Life Strategy Seminars) - Growth through Relationships, Series 4 (Box 10, Reel 5)
  - Strategies for Daily Living (Life Strategy Seminars) - Leadership, undated; Series 4 (Box 11, Cassette 27)
  - Strategies for Daily Living (Life Strategy Seminars) - Managing your Time, undated; Series 4 (Box 16, Cassette 9)
  - Strategies for Daily Living (Life Strategy Seminars) - Modification of Behavior/Developing Self Reliance, undated; Series 4 (Box 11, Cassette 28)
  - Strategies for Daily Living (Life Strategy Seminars) - Modification of Behavior/Developing Self Reliance, undated; Series 4 (Box 16, Cassette 10)
  - Strategies for Daily Living (Life Strategy Seminars) - The Need for Acceptance, undated; Series 4 (Box 11, Cassette 29)
  - Strategies for Daily Living (Life Strategy Seminars) - The Need for Acceptance, undated; Series 4 (Box 16, Cassette 11)
  - Strategies for Daily Living (Life Strategy Seminars) - Goal Selection/Step by Step Planning, undated; Series 4 (Box 11, Cassette 30)
  - Strategies for Daily Living (Life Strategy Seminars) - Goal Selection/Step by Step Planning, undated; Series 4 (Box 16, Cassette 12)
  - Strategies for Daily Living (Life Strategy Seminars) - Philosophy of Life, undated; Series 4 (Box 16, Cassette 13)
  - Strategies for Daily Living (Life Strategy Seminars) - Leadership, undated; Series 4 (Box 16, Cassette 14)
  - Strategies for Daily Living (Life Strategy Seminars) - The Mastery of Stress, undated; Series 4 (Box 16, Cassette 15)
  - Sunrise Semester - Magic, Faith, and Healing - course review, 01/06/1976; Series 4; U-matic videocassette (Box 15, Videocassette 13)
  - Sunrise Semester - Magic, Faith, and Healing - 2, 09/09/1975; Series 4 (Box 10, Reel 1)
  - Sunrise Semester - Magic, Faith, and Healing - 4, undated; Series 4 (Box 14, Videocassette 1)
  - Sunrise Semester - Magic, Faith, and Healing - 12 [1 of 2], undated; Series 4; U-matic videocassette (Box 14, Videocassette 2)
  - Sunrise Semester - Magic, Faith, and Healing - 12 [2 of 2], undated; Series 4; U-matic videocassette (Box 14, Videocassette 3)
  - Sunrise Semester - Magic, Faith, and Healing - 14 - Culture Bound Disorders [1 of 2], 10/07/1975; Series 4; U-matic videocassette (Box 15, Videocassette 1)
  - Sunrise Semester - Magic, Faith, and Healing - 14 - Culture Bound Disorders [2 of 2], 10/07/1975; Series 4; U-matic videocassette (Box 15, Videocassette 2)
  - Sunrise Semester - Magic, Faith, and Healing - 16, 10/09/1975; Series 4; U-matic videocassette (Box 15, Videocassette 4)
  - Sunrise Semester - Magic, Faith, and Healing - 22, 10/16/1975; Series 4; U-matic videocassette (Box 15, Videocassette 6)
  - Sunrise Semester - Magic, Faith, and Healing - 24, undated; Series 4; U-matic videocassette (Box 14, Videocassette 4)
  - Sunrise Semester - Magic, Faith, and Healing - 26 - Herbalist, 10/13/1975; Series 4; U-matic videocassette (Box 15, Videocassette 5)
  - Sunrise Semester - Magic, Faith, and Healing - 30, 10/25/1975; Series 4; U-matic videocassette (Box 15, Videocassette 7)
  - Sunrise Semester - Magic, Faith, and Healing - 31 - Death, 01/13/1976; Series 4; U-matic videocassette (Box 15, Videocassette 14)
  - Sunrise Semester - Magic, Faith, and Healing - 34, undated; Series 4; U-matic videocassette (Box 14, Videocassette 5)
  - Sunrise Semester - Magic, Faith, and Healing - 38, 11/01/1975; Series 4; U-matic videocassette (Box 15, Videocassette 8)
  - Sunrise Semester - Magic, Faith, and Healing - 38, 11/04/1975; Series 4; U-matic videocassette (Box 15, Videocassette 10)
  - Sunrise Semester - Magic, Faith, and Healing - 39, 11/18/1975; Series 4 (Box 10, Reel 2)
  - Sunrise Semester - Magic, Faith, and Healing - 40, 11/06/1975; Series 4; U-matic videocassette (Box 15, Videocassette 9)
  - Sunrise Semester - Magic, Faith, and Healing - 40, 12/27/1975; Series 4 (Box 10, Reel 3)